I received this because I passed
your test, Iorygoi-san.
It's a very precious bottle.
When the bottle is filled to the brim, that's
when I can go to the place of my wishes.
Right, Ioryogi-san?
When do you think it will fill up?
I can't wait, can you?
Let's get this straight...
You are the one who is going to fill it, Kobato!
Kobato.
Dou sureba iin dakke?
Atarimae no kototte itsumo
Muzukashii na
Ureshii toki waratte
Suki na toki ni utaitai dake
Na no ni
Itsuka negai wa kanau to
Demo "itsuka" tte dore kurai?
Machikirenai yo
123! no aizu de ryoute hirogete
Zenshin ni hikari wo atsumete
Doko ni aru no?
Oshiete, watashi ni dekiru koto
Meippai kizu tsuite
Seiippai hashitte
Nan juu kai koronde naite
Sore de mo mada
Akireru kurai
Ashita wo shinjiteru
Hanato Kobato!
Yes sir!
...The Shining Kompeito.
Now listen!
Nothing is going to happen with that bottle,
unless you do something about it!
...The Shining Kompeito.
What is it that you're going to fill it with?!
Sir! I'm going to fill it with
people's broken hearts, sir!
And how are you going to collect those hearts?!
Sir! I must heal those broken hearts first, sir!
Good. As long as you understand.
Well then, we have no time to waste!
Yes sir!
Oh, I forgot to tell you.
Don't talk to me when humans are nearby.
Huh? Why am I not allowed?
I'm only going to explain this to you,
since you obviously lack in memory,
knowledge and common sense,
but here, stuffed toys don't talk.
Talking to things that don't
talk is considered strange.
Do you understand?!
Why don't they talk?
Because they are stuffed toys.
Why does being a stuffed toy
keep them from talking?
Never mind, just go!
Okay! Kobato is ready!
Why did you have to jump off the seesaw?!
Anybody with a broken heart?
Anybody who would like to be healed?
Please let me heal your heart!
I-I'm good, thanks...
Excuse me! Isn't there something I
can help you with healing?
Oh, give me a break.
Is there something I can help you with?!
Rock, paper, scissors.
Rock, paper...
Can you help us?
Sure, what can I do for you?
Can you be "it" for kick the can?
It? I can help you by being "it"?
Yes! Please?
Okay! I'll do my best!
I kicked the can!
Huh? That's funny. The bottle is still empty.
What were you going to heal by
being it in kick the can?
Where are you going to find a heart
that needs healing that way?
Did I do something wrong?
All you were doing was being their playmate.
Really...
I guess it's not easy running into
someone who needs healing.
But, but!
The fact that there's nobody out
there that needs healing
means that there's nobody out there that's hurt
or feeling sad, which is a good thing.
Is there no limit to your positive thinking?
Yomogi Station
I just hope I can find a way to help.
Uh... h-hi...
Uh... p-please...
This is... for me?
Uh, yes. Please take it.
To be able to give strangers something so
special, without the slightest bit of hesitation.
What a wonderful person!
Oh, come on.
I still have this much more to hand out.
It would be a great help if you
could take as many as you like.
Really?!
Then I'll take them all!
Huh?
Wow, thanks! You saved me!
I was able to help him out and
look what I got in return!
Now what are you going to do with all that?
Now it's my turn to give out
these wonderful gifts!
Huh?
Here you are! Aren't these terrific tissues?
They'll come in handy, I promise. Here!
Here! Here! Here! Here!
I'll give you as many as you like!
Uh... I'm good... thanks.
Go ahead! There's no need to hesitate.
Please! Here!
Have a pack of lovely tissues! Please!
That hurt.
I-I'm sorry!
Hey.
Yes!
Stop wandering around in
the middle of the street.
I'm sorry!
That guy...
From the other day...
Pick up those tissues, would you?
Please wait! Um, I need to thank you!
I'm sure he came this way.
The sheet flew off!
Over here, Ms. Sayaka!
What are you doing?
Oh my goodness!
Are you alright?
Yes...
She scratched her nose!
Huh?!
You're right!
I'm so embarrassed!
You two! That was impolite.
Yes, Teacher Sayaka.
I'm so sorry.
I work here at Yomogi Kindergarten.
We're understaffed you see, so we got
delayed in bringing the laundry in.
You don't have enough people?!
Ah, that's right.
Is that a problem?!
Y-You could say so.
Would it help if you had enough people?!
Well...
Would it help?!
Uh, y-yes!
I will help you!
Huh?
Uh, this is for you!
Thank you.
So, what's your name?
I'm Toshihiko!
My name is Kobato Hanato.
Kobato? What a weird name.
What a weird name!
Do you think so?
Then your father's name must be Obato!
Well it isn't.
Then what is it?
What is it?!
Uh, well...
His name.
What's his name?
Come on.
What is it? Tell me.
Hey.
Yes?
Do you... not have a father?
Probably not.
Never mind about the name.
Right.
Come on, let's play! Come on!
Now children, don't be causing trouble.
Yes, Ms. Sayaka!
Oh, I would like to help with something.
You'd be a great help just carrying on
with the children like you were.
Carrying on? Uh, well...
Miss Kobato?
Yes?
Play the organ!
I'm sorry, I don't know how to play the organ.
Is that so.
I'm sorry. But I can dance with you.
You dance?
Yes!
Wait here, okay?
Mr. Kiyokazu, will you play the organ?
Oh!
I wanna dance with Teacher Kobato.
She's no teacher.
Then just plain Kobato!
What's the big idea? You followed me here.
Huh? I just wanted to thank you properly.
Never mind. Go home.
But I'm helping out here.
You can't even play the organ.
You're of no use here.
Oh? Are you two friends?
No, we are not!
Oh. Well in that case, this is Kiyokazu Fujimoto
who has been working here with me.
And this is Kobato.
I'm counting on your help today.
Yes ma'am!
Don't get in my way.
Mr. Kiyokazu, hurry up and play the organ!
Hurry, teacher!
You two keep them happy, all right?
Kobato, come on!
Let's dance!
What in the world is that?
This person is mean!
But I'm not going to let that get to me!
Wow!
Kobato, you're funny!
Is this a place where children live?
They don't actually live here.
We look after them during the day.
I see.
But you know, this place is pretty old.
With new kindergartens opening up nearby,
we're seeing fewer and fewer students.
However!
We'll just have to hang in there!
Yep. Not worth worrying about.
You're right. It's exactly as you say, Fujimoto.
And thank you, Kobato.
You were a great help today.
The children had a good time.
Oh, no, I uh.
I was just playing with them.
I mean, Ioryogi-san always
gets angry with me and...
Oh no! Ioryogi-san is gone!
Oh, I didn't know you had someone with you.
Yes! Uh, well I guess you wouldn't say
"someone," he's a stuffed animal person!
Well he can't talk, so if I don't go
and get him, he'll scold me!
Goodbye!
Um... can I come again tomorrow?
If it's alright with you...
Ms. Sayaka.
We have no idea where she's
from or what she does.
Are you sure it's safe to let her in
and out of the kindergarten?
You do know about me!
My name is Kobato Hanato!
You think your name says everything about you?
I am...
You're what?
I'm in the middle of my search.
Oh, my.
Well then Kobato, if it's not inconvenient for
you, we'd be happy to have you here.
We can't pay you very much, though.
Oh no! If you would let me help,
that's plenty for me!
Why thank you.
Hey...
Yes?
Just one thing...
If you're here out of sympathy or curiosity,
we don't need you.
Huh?
We're sick and tired of people feeling
sorry for us. It's uncalled-for.
Well that's not how I feel!
Um...
Uncalled-for...
You want to know what's uncalled-for?
Suddenly leaving me alone in the
middle of town is uncalled-for!
It's a good thing I found you, Ioryogi-san.
No it isn't!
Do you have any idea how hard it is to
move about a little bit at a time,
trying not to be noticed?!
I'm sorry!
I told you didn't I? Here, I am a stuffed toy and
stuffed toys do not walk around on their own!
I'm sorry!
Never mind the bottle, you even
forgot to take me with you!
The bottle!
Just as I thought.
What do you mean, just as you thought?
Did you think there'd be something in there?
I guess what I'm doing isn't
helping to heal anyone at all.
In fact...
I wonder if it's uncalled-for.
Mr. Fujimoto looked hurt.
But he said I was uncalled-for.
Well. I guess it depends on the person.
If there are people in the world who are hurt
and those who are not, of those who are,
I hadn't realized that there are people who
want to be healed and those who don't.
So?
Yes?
What do you want to do about it?
I...
You want to heal, don't you? Then go and heal!
Would it be okay?
Think about whether it was okay or
not after you've actually healed.
Yes sir!
Why that's...
Toshihiko?
Kobato!
What about nursery school?
Are you on your way home?
Mhm. But not yet.
You like the swing?
No. It's not my favorite. But I've got to stay
here awhile longer until my mom gets back.
She's working.
She works, does she?
But...
My mom really works hard!
It's hard because she got divorced,
but she still makes breakfast for me!
And she's really kind! Really!
That's great!
Aren't you going to tell me how bad she is?
Why is she bad?
Toshihiko, is your mother late
coming to get you again?
Uh-huh
Oh... You're such a good boy,
Toshihiko, without even complaining.
She's late again today too? You're such a
good child, Toshihiko. Patiently waiting.
If only she would be more considerate
and put herself in Toshihiko's position.
Really.
I mean I realize she's busy, but you know...
It certainly is a problem.
They all talk about what a bad mother she is.
That she should do better.
Is she a bad mother?
No way! She's doing everything she can!
Really! She's awesome! She's the best!
That's wonderful!
Your awesome mom who works hard...
I think she's super!
Really?
Yes. She's a wonderful mother.
Wh-What's the matter?!
Does it hurt somewhere?
No!
Really?
Yes...
What?!
Th-There's something in here! But, but... why?!
That must have belonged to Toshihiko.
Toshihiko?
You can do it, Kobato!
I think you made him happy, saying nice things
about his mother and being nice to him yourself.
Huh? Do you think I was kind to him?
No matter how kindly you treat someone,
if you're looking for something in
return, you'll never be healing.
Just do what you want to do
and I think you'll be all right.
Yes.
I am going to work hard at collecting
people's broken hearts!
Wait a minute!
You're sounding like you're going to go
around breaking people's hearts
so you can collect them.
Should I say I'm going to collect healed hearts?
That sounds like you're going to heal
the heart and then take it away.
Then what should I call this thing I just received?
Oh what a nuisance!
That looks like a kompeito candy
so just call it kompeito!
Kompeito... okay. I'm going
to call these kompeito.
Hey Kobato!
Yes?
Leaving me behind was out of the question, but
for being your first time, you did very well.
So I'm going to give you a bonus. You get a
score of one hundred points today!
And we're going to keep it up,
aren't we, Kobato?
Yes sir! Kobato is ready!
Oh but, you're not going to let the hundred
points get to your head, now are you?
Huh? But you're always
telling me to use my head.
That's not what I meant!
Well then what did you mean?
Never mind. I'm taking the hundred points back!
What?! No way!
Hito wa mina tonde mitai no ni
Juuryoku ni damasareterunda
Dare mo honto wa toberunda yo
Ano ko ga anna ni kanashisou na no wa
Jibun no kage wo
Dokoka ni wasurete kichatta kara kamo
Sore nara
"Arigatou," tte kimi ni ietara
"Arigatou," tte kimi ga waraeba
Ittari kitari ureshiku naru
Kimi ga shiawase ni naru
Shinpai nante iranai yo
Issho ni iru kara
Ureshikuttemo namida ga deru nante
Fushigi da
Next episode
...A Gift from the Rain.
Fushigi da
Next episode
...A Gift from the Rain.